TRENTON HICKS

Sioux City, IA | (712)-522-0332 | trentonmhicks@gmail.com | trentonhicks.com

SUMMARY

Software developer with over 4 years of front-end web development experience and 1+ years of experience with back-end development. I am proficient at collaborating with others and very attentive to details. I love to solve challenging problems and spend my free time building projects to enhance my skillset

EDUCATION

Codeflip Sergeant Bluff, IA 2019 to 2020

NET Software Development

CERTIFICATIONS

- Pending Microsoft Programming in C#
- HubSpot Inbound Marketing
- Free Code Camp Responsive Web Design

SKILLS & ABILITIES

Methods

- Domain Driven Design
- Mediator
- State machine patterns
- Agile Development

Technologies

 C#, SQL Server, .NET Core, ASP.NET Core, ADO.NET, Entity Framework, Azure Service Bus, MediatR, HTML, CSS / SCSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, Vue.js, JSON, XML, LINQ, Git, AJAX.

EXPERIENCE

.NET Developer

August 2019 to Present

Warren Software Consulting

- Communicated with clients to better understand their needs.
- Fixed bugs in various projects including legacy codebases.
- Created websites.
- Worked with SQL Server

Web Developer Antidote 71

Nov 2017 to Feb 2020

- Collaborated with a team of designers and marketers to build new website projects.
- Participated in client meetings to provide support and better understand their needs.
- Provided recurring web maintenance and content updates for existing clients.
- Created documentation for projects that I had built.
- Trained web development intern.

ONLINE COURSES

- Vue: Getting Started
- Developing Faster with the Vue CLI
- WordPress theme development with Bootstrap
- Ultimate Web Designer & Developer Course: Build 23 Projects!
- Web Hosting 101: Get Your Website Live on the Web in No Time
- Ultimate AngularJS: Build a Real-World App from Scratch
- Practical PHP: Master the Basics and Code Dynamic Websites
- The Sass Course: Learn Sass for Real-World Websites